<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kent Sommer</title>
    <link>https://kentsommer.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kent Sommer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2021 Kent Sommer</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kentsommer.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://kentsommer.com/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kentsommer.com/home/about/</guid>
      <description>Biography I am currently a Software Engineer at Toyota Research Institute (secondeed to Woven Planet in Tokyo, JP). My out of work interests include tinkering with machine learning, computer vision, and mobile robotics projects. I have diverse US and international work experience across the fields of software engineering and robotics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selected Publications</title>
      <link>https://kentsommer.com/home/publications_selected/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kentsommer.com/home/publications_selected/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks</title>
      <link>https://kentsommer.com/home/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kentsommer.com/home/talks/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Posts</title>
      <link>https://kentsommer.com/home/posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kentsommer.com/home/posts/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://kentsommer.com/home/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kentsommer.com/home/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://kentsommer.com/home/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kentsommer.com/home/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HireVue: Misapplied Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://kentsommer.com/post/hirevue-misapplied-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kentsommer.com/post/hirevue-misapplied-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Behavioral interviews are about showing your interviewer how you respond in a variety of situations. But beyond that, they help give the interviewer a sense of who you are and if you have a good &amp;ldquo;culture fit&amp;rdquo; with the company. At a really high level then, behavioral interviews are about people.
It came as a bit of a shock then to hear about the interview experience of a few colleagues who encountered the video interview process created by HireVue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recovering Arch Linux after a side-by-side install</title>
      <link>https://kentsommer.com/post/recovering-arch-linux-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kentsommer.com/post/recovering-arch-linux-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>If another OS (also *nix based) is installed alongside arch, grub will likely get messed up on the arch side of things. Grub will see the arch linux boot option, however, upon startup it will throw a kernel panic with the error:
Not syncing: VFS Unable to mount root fs on unknown-block.  This is caused by a bug in the way some other linux distros generate the grub.cfg file. If you have the above error, your grub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards accurate kidnap resolution through deep learning</title>
      <link>https://kentsommer.com/publication/kidnap-resolution-through-deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kentsommer.com/publication/kidnap-resolution-through-deep-learning/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards Accurate Kidnap Resolution Through Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://kentsommer.com/talk/example-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kentsommer.com/talk/example-talk/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Value Iteration Networks</title>
      <link>https://kentsommer.com/project/pytorch-vin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kentsommer.com/project/pytorch-vin/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Journey Through Platforms</title>
      <link>https://kentsommer.com/post/a-journey-through-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kentsommer.com/post/a-journey-through-platforms/</guid>
      <description>So, it has been some time since my last post&amp;hellip; Before I get into the fun stuff (well&amp;hellip; fun for me anyways), let me give you a bit of a life update! Having already finished 1/4th of my masters, I can say with confidence that I am really happy that I decided to continue on and get an advanced degree. I&amp;rsquo;m able to work with world-class researchers on amazing topics doing work that has the potential to drastically improve people&amp;rsquo;s lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inception V4</title>
      <link>https://kentsommer.com/project/keras-inceptionv4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kentsommer.com/project/keras-inceptionv4/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Touch Location Inference (Side Channel Attack)</title>
      <link>https://kentsommer.com/project/web-based-touch-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kentsommer.com/project/web-based-touch-inference/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter is Coming</title>
      <link>https://kentsommer.com/post/winter-is-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kentsommer.com/post/winter-is-coming/</guid>
      <description>As I groggily walked out of my dorm and into the crisp Fall air this morning it became readily apparent that Winter was indeed on its way. It is that extra little bite to the air that wasn&amp;rsquo;t present a few days ago. Midterms have come and gone uneventfully which in my mind is a good thing. I did find out a rather crazy fact about tests for undergraduates here at KAIST though&amp;hellip; apparently, most tests give you as much time as you want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tensors, Baseball, and a whole lot of fun</title>
      <link>https://kentsommer.com/post/tensors-baseball-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kentsommer.com/post/tensors-baseball-fun/</guid>
      <description>It has taken a while for me to really feel settled in here, but I think I&amp;rsquo;ve finally crossed that line and I&amp;rsquo;m starting to feel really blessed to be here.
The last couple weeks have been an absolute blast and given the fact that I basically get to build cool things every day, so should the rest of my time here. As far as classes go&amp;hellip; I can&amp;rsquo;t really pick out many differences so far compared to the structure of similar graduate level courses in the US.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reality Sets In</title>
      <link>https://kentsommer.com/post/reality-sets-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kentsommer.com/post/reality-sets-in/</guid>
      <description>Well, I&amp;rsquo;m finally here. I think often I let myself get caught up in the negative aspects of a new place or experience so in this post I will focus on everything good here at KAIST so far. The transition to living in a dorm after having my own space for the better part of my life has actually been very smooth so far. I have an awesome roommate, and the dorm facilities are clean and bright.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Curious Case of Dunkin Doughnuts</title>
      <link>https://kentsommer.com/post/the-curious-case-of-dunkin-doughnuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kentsommer.com/post/the-curious-case-of-dunkin-doughnuts/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s 8:45 in the morning, sweat is already dripping down my back as the heat from the past few weeks still hasn&amp;rsquo;t cleared. Suddenly a familiar but unplaceable tune starts playing over the subway station speakers signaling that the train is almost here. As I, and everyone else, are jostled into place by the crowed moving onto the train I realize I haven&amp;rsquo;t had breakfast yet. Where do I finally end up you might ask?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drones, Friends, and Navigation</title>
      <link>https://kentsommer.com/post/drones-friends-navigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kentsommer.com/post/drones-friends-navigation/</guid>
      <description>Wednesday came and went and once evening hit I realized I had to switch things up. I had been letting myself worry about every small thing that needed to happen once I was on campus and how difficult everything would be once there&amp;hellip; it was eating away at me. I&amp;rsquo;ve never felt homesick before, but this was as close as I would ever like to get again. I tried to remember back to my last trip here to figure out what was causing it and came to the conclusion that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t keeping myself nearly busy enough this time around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Things Started</title>
      <link>https://kentsommer.com/post/getting-things-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kentsommer.com/post/getting-things-started/</guid>
      <description>As I write this, I&amp;rsquo;m happy to say I am finally here in Korea and gazing off at the mountain view from my residence in Seoul. I walked around a bit yesterday which ended up being very nostalgic as memories of late night ramen trips, daily bus rides, and familiar places came floating back to me. It almost feels like I never left&amp;hellip; Over the past 48 hours, one thing has become increasingly apparent, though, I really need to step up my studying game for Korean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparations and History</title>
      <link>https://kentsommer.com/post/preparations-and-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kentsommer.com/post/preparations-and-history/</guid>
      <description>If I was asked to imagine four years ago where I would be today, never in my wildest dreams would I imagine myself here, yet, here I am, 50 days out from one of the biggest adventures of my life. In 50 short days, I will be boarding a plane for South Korea where I will be spending at least the next two years of my life. Now, this begs the question, how did I get here?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D Object Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://kentsommer.com/project/3d-object-reconstruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kentsommer.com/project/3d-object-reconstruction/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>