<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technical on Kent Sommer</title>
    <link>https://kentsommer.com/tags/technical/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technical on Kent Sommer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2021 Kent Sommer</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kentsommer.com/tags/technical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>HireVue: Misapplied Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://kentsommer.com/post/hirevue-misapplied-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kentsommer.com/post/hirevue-misapplied-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Behavioral interviews are about showing your interviewer how you respond in a variety of situations. But beyond that, they help give the interviewer a sense of who you are and if you have a good &amp;ldquo;culture fit&amp;rdquo; with the company. At a really high level then, behavioral interviews are about people.
It came as a bit of a shock then to hear about the interview experience of a few colleagues who encountered the video interview process created by HireVue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recovering Arch Linux after a side-by-side install</title>
      <link>https://kentsommer.com/post/recovering-arch-linux-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kentsommer.com/post/recovering-arch-linux-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>If another OS (also *nix based) is installed alongside arch, grub will likely get messed up on the arch side of things. Grub will see the arch linux boot option, however, upon startup it will throw a kernel panic with the error:
Not syncing: VFS Unable to mount root fs on unknown-block.  This is caused by a bug in the way some other linux distros generate the grub.cfg file. If you have the above error, your grub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Journey Through Platforms</title>
      <link>https://kentsommer.com/post/a-journey-through-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kentsommer.com/post/a-journey-through-platforms/</guid>
      <description>So, it has been some time since my last post&amp;hellip; Before I get into the fun stuff (well&amp;hellip; fun for me anyways), let me give you a bit of a life update! Having already finished 1/4th of my masters, I can say with confidence that I am really happy that I decided to continue on and get an advanced degree. I&amp;rsquo;m able to work with world-class researchers on amazing topics doing work that has the potential to drastically improve people&amp;rsquo;s lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tensors, Baseball, and a whole lot of fun</title>
      <link>https://kentsommer.com/post/tensors-baseball-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kentsommer.com/post/tensors-baseball-fun/</guid>
      <description>It has taken a while for me to really feel settled in here, but I think I&amp;rsquo;ve finally crossed that line and I&amp;rsquo;m starting to feel really blessed to be here.
The last couple weeks have been an absolute blast and given the fact that I basically get to build cool things every day, so should the rest of my time here. As far as classes go&amp;hellip; I can&amp;rsquo;t really pick out many differences so far compared to the structure of similar graduate level courses in the US.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>